Guide to the Navy V-12 program, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Navy V-12 program, Yale University, records
1943-1949
RU 586
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
8.5
(15 boxes)
The records consist of student files, memoranda, correspondence, and rosters documenting the Navy V-12 Unit at Yale. Included is correspondence between the Navy and Yale University documenting the establishment of the Navy V-12 program at Yale.
Yale University. Navy V-12 Program
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 42-A (YRG 42-A), Records of military training programs at Yale.
Conditions Governing Access
While this collection as a whole is available for research, parts of it are restricted due to law and university policy. Any restricted material will be noted as such. See Collection Contents for details.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of student files, memoranda, correspondence, and rosters documenting the Navy V-12 Unit at Yale. Included is correspondence between the Navy and Yale University documenting the establishment of the Navy V-12 program at Yale.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Military education -- United States; Military training camps -- United States; World War, 1939-1945 -- Education and the war; World War, 1939-1945 -- War work -- Schools; World War, 1939-1945 -- United States; United States. Navy ( History World War, 1939-1945); United States. Navy; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Navy V-12 Program
- Records of withdrawn students, circa 1943-1949; Accession 19ND-A-177
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2025.
  - Coast Guard: Transcripts list, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Navy, Marines, Coast Guard
    - General: lists, memoranda, correspondence, 1943-44 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Students assigned to Yale, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Test candidates, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Roster of Yale Navy V-12 Unit Trainees Separated
    - Marines, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Navy (including Coast Guard), 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Marines, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Navy, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Navy, 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Marines, 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Records of the World War II Division N training program, circa 1943-1946; Accession 1949-A-002
  Naterials located in boxes 1-8 are closed until January 1, 2021 as established by Yale Corporation regulations. Materials in boxes 9-10 are open for research.
  - Yale Navy V-12 Units -- Student Records
    - Summer Term, 1943-1944
      Material is restricted until January 1, 2021 due to University policy.
      - N3.10 Change of Status (more than one student), 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - N3.10 Change of Status (A-Z), 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 2 - 3)
      - N7.10 General, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - N12.10 Lists, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - N20.10 Separation from Unit, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - N20.20 Students - General, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Fall Term, 1943-1944
      - N3.10 Change of Status (more than one student), 1943-1944 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - N3.10 Change of Status (A-Z), 1943-1944 (Box 2, Folder 9 - 10)
      - N7.10 General, 1943-1944 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - N12.10 Lists, 1943-1944 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - N20.10 Separation from Unit, 1943-1944 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - N20.20 Students-General, 1943-1944 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Spring Term, 1943-1944
      - N3.10 Change of Status (more than one student), 1943-1944 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - N3.10 Change of Status (A-Z), 1943-1944 (Box 3, Folder 16 - 17)
      - N7.10 General, 1943-1944 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - N12.10 Lists, 1943-1944 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - N20.10 Separation from Unit, 1943-1944 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - N20.20 Students-General, 1943-1944 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Summer Term, 1944-1945
      - N3.10 Change of Status (more than one student), 1944-1945 (Box 4, Folder 22)
      - N3.10 Change of Status (A-Z), 1944-1945 (Box 4, Folder 23 - 24)
      - N7.10 General, 1944-1945 (Box 4, Folder 25)
      - N12.10 Lists, 1944-1945 (Box 4, Folder 26)
      - N20.10 Separation from Unit, 1944-1945 (Box 4, Folder 27)
      - N20.20 Students - General, 1944-1945 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Fall Term, 1944-1945
      - N3.10 Change of Status (more than one student), 1944-1945 (Box 5, Folder 29)
      - N3.10 Change of Status (A-Z), 1944-1945 (Box 5, Folder 30 - 31)
      - N7.10 General, 1944-1945 (Box 5, Folder 32)
      - N12.10 Lists, 1944-1945 (Box 5, Folder 33)
      - N20.10 Separation from Unit, 1944-1945 (Box 5, Folder 34)
      - N20.20 Students-General, 1944-1945 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Spring Term, 1944-1945
      - N3.10 Change of Status (more than one student), 1944-1945 (Box 5, Folder 36)
      - N3.10 Change of Status (A-Z), 1944-1945 (Box 5, Folder 37 - 38)
      - N7.10 General, 1944-1945 (Box 5, Folder 39)
      - N12.10 Lists, 1944-1945 (Box 6, Folder 40)
      - N20.10 Separation from Unit, 1944-1945 (Box 6, Folder 41)
      - N20.20 Students-General, 1944-1945 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Summer Term, 1945-1946
      - N3.10 Change of Status (more than one student), 1945-1946 (Box 6, Folder 43)
      - N3.10 Change of Status (A-Z), 1945-1946 (Box 6, Folder 44 - 45)
      - N7.10 General, 1945-1946 (Box 6, Folder 46)
      - N12.10 Lists, 1945-1946 (Box 6, Folder 47)
      - N20.10 Separation from Unit, 1945-1946 (Box 6, Folder 48)
      - N20.20 Students-General, 1945-1946 (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - Fall Term, 1945-1946
      - N3.10 Change of Status (more than one student), 1945-1946 (Box 7, Folder 50)
      - N3.10 Change of Status (A-Z), 1945-1946 (Box 7, Folder 51 - 52)
      - N7.10 General, 1945-1946 (Box 7, Folder 53)
      - N12.10 Lists, 1945-1946 (Box 7, Folder 54)
      - N20.10 Separation from Unit, 1945-1946 (Box 7, Folder 55)
      - N20.10 Separation from Unit (Navy blanks on trainees leaving the end of term), 1945-1946 (Box 7, Folder 56)
      - N20.20 Students-General, 1945-1946 (Box 7, Folder 57)
    - Spring Term, 1945-1946
      - N3.10 Change of Status (more than one student), 1945-1946 (Box 7, Folder 58)
      - N3.10 Change of Status (A-Z), 1945-1946 (Box 7, Folder 59 - 60)
      - N7.10 General, 1945-1946 (Box 7, Folder 61)
      - N12.10 Lists, 1945-1946 (Box 8, Folder 62)
      - N20.10 Separation from Unit, 1945-1946 (Box 8, Folder 63)
      - N20.20 Students-General, 1945-1946 (Box 8, Folder 64)
    - Students Previously Enrolled (N20.201), 1946 (Box 8, Folder 65)
    - Summer Session (N20.30), 1946 (Box 8, Folder 66)
    - Rosters of Unit - Trainees Separated
      - Navy (including Coast Guard), 1943-1944 (Box 8, Folder 67)
      - Marines, 1943-1944 (Box 8, Folder 68)
      - Navy, 1944-1945 (Box 8, Folder 69)
      - Marines, 1944-1945 (Box 8, Folder 70)
      - Navy, 1945-1946 (Box 8, Folder 71)
      - Marines, 1945-1946 (Box 8, Folder 72)
      - Navy Test Scores, 1943-45 (Box 8, Folder 73)
  - Student Records: Alphabetical by student
    - 1945WF B-S withdrawn (Box 2)
    - 1946M A-Sh (Box 2)
    - 1946M Si-Z (Box 3)
    - 1946N A-J (Box 3)
    - 1946N K-Z (Box 4)
    - 1947M F-W (Box 4)
    - 1947J A-Me (Box 4)
    - 19473 Mu-Z (Box 5)
    - 1948 A-Z (Box 5)
    - 1949 A-Z (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, Lists; Statistics
    - Preparation for War: Navy-University Correspondence before the opening of the V-12, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 74)
    - Maps of Navy Colleges (Residential), 1943 (Box 9, Folder 75)
    - Navy Courses, including Bulletins, 1943-1944 (Box 9, Folder 76)
    - Navy V-12 Testing--Admissions Officer Data, 1944 March (Box 9, Folder 77)
    - Classification Lists, 1943-1946 (Box 9, Folder 78 - 82)
    - College Lists, Rosters, 1943-1944 (Box 9, Folder 83 - 84)
    - College Lists, Rosters, 1944-1946 (Box 10, Folder 85 - 92)
    - Statistics, 1943-1946 (Box 10, Folder 93 - 95)